Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have another holiday lesson for you guys.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家带来另一节节日课程。
It's an intermediate level lesson, but it's not about Christmas and it's not about New
这是一节中级课程，但内容既不是关于圣诞节，也不是关于新年。
Year's.
新年。
So what's this holiday, Marco?
那这是什么节日呢，Marco？
It's like after Christmas, but before New Year's.
它就像圣诞节之后、新年之前的一个节日。
Okay, so let's look at this holiday in today's vocabulary preview.
好的，那我们先来看看今天词汇预览中的这个节日。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right, so as you noticed in the title, this is called Boxing Day.
好的，正如你在标题中注意到的，这个节日叫节礼日。
So like fighting boxing or...
所以是像拳击那种打斗，还是……
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
Kind of like boxes, right?
有点像盒子，对吧？
It's more related to boxes.
它跟盒子更相关。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is a holiday that we don't actually celebrate in America.
所以这个节日在美国其实并不过。
It's celebrated in what are called Commonwealth countries.
它在所谓的英联邦国家庆祝。
That means countries that used to be a part of Great Britain or that are a part of Great
这意味着那些曾经是大不列颠一部分或现在属于大不列颠的国家。
Britain.
英国。
So England, Scotland, Canada, Australia.
比如英格兰、苏格兰、加拿大、澳大利亚。
And this is a day where, well, it's considered a holiday because it's a bank holiday.
这一天之所以被视为节日，是因为它是一个银行假日。
That means all the banks close.
也就是说所有银行都关门。
No one's at work.
没人上班。
It's the day after Christmas.
它是圣诞节后的第二天。
So it's December 26th and it's traditionally a day when you give money or gifts to the
所以是12月26日，传统上这一天你会给穷人送钱或礼物。
poor.
穷人。
Okay.
好的。
And so this is more or less what we're going to be talking about, but more modern, right?
所以我们大概要聊的就是这个，但更现代一些，对吧？
Before it was like that, but now it's kind of become this shopping thing, right?
以前是这样，但现在它变成了购物日，对吧？
It has.
确实如此。
It's a day when everyone goes to the sales after Christmas to return things or to buy
这一天大家都会在圣诞节后去打折季退货或买新东西。
new things.
新东西。
So we're going to hear about this right away in today's dialogue.
所以我们马上会在今天的对话中听到这个。
And when we come back, we'll be talking about some of the phrases and words that you've
等我们回来，我们会讨论你听到的一些短语和单词。
heard.
听到的。
What do you think of this one?
你觉得这个怎么样？
Eh, so-so.
嗯，一般般。
And this one?
那这个呢？
Too flashy?
太花哨了？
Nah, not too flashy.
不，不算太花哨。
Oh, and this sweater from my aunt.
哦，还有我姑姑送的这件毛衣。
Isn't it hideous?
是不是很丑？
I guess.
是吧。
Are you even listening?
你到底有没有在听？
I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
我想跟你聊聊天。
And I'm trying to watch the game, but you're yapping on about your new clothes.
而我想看比赛，但你一直在唠叨你的新衣服。
Well I have to decide which gifts to keep and which to exchange for better ones when
好吧，我得决定哪些礼物留下，哪些在今天下午去节礼日打折时换成更好的。
I go to the Boxing Day sales this afternoon.
节礼日打折。
Well could you do me the favor of making this quick?
那你能不能帮我个忙，快点搞定？
It's the third quarter and you've been blabbering on since the first.
现在是第三节了，你从第一节就开始喋喋不休。
Oh, your precious game.
哦，你宝贵的比赛。
You watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at
你每年都看同一场比赛，每年你心爱的主队至少输三个球。
least three goals.
三个球。
Oh, no you didn't.
哦，你居然敢这么说。
You didn't just insult the Salisbury Seals, did you?
你刚才没侮辱索尔兹伯里海豹队吧？
Why don't you just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until the sales
你不如去退掉所有那些愚蠢的衣服，等打折结束再回来。
are over?
打折结束。
I might just.
我可能真会这么做。
Enjoy your stupid game.
享受你愚蠢的比赛吧。
And Merry Christmas.
还有圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
Alright, great, so we're back and interesting, the couple fighting right after Christmas.
好的，我们回来了，有意思，这对夫妻在圣诞节后吵架。
Well I think it's very common to hear fights around the holidays.
嗯，我觉得节日期间听到吵架很常见。
People are very stressed out.
人们压力很大。
And tired of dealing with family and presents and all the stress, right?
而且厌倦了应付家人、礼物和所有压力，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
But we'll talk about that a little bit later on.
但我们稍后会再聊这个。
Right now why don't we take a look at four key words in language takeaway.
现在，我们不如先看看语言要点中的四个关键词。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, these first two words are words that the wife uses in talking about some of these
好的，前两个词是妻子在谈论她收到的一些衣服礼物时用的。
clothes that she got as presents.
礼物。
So she says, well she asks her husband, is this too flashy?
所以她问丈夫，这件太花哨了吗？
Flashy.
花哨。
Alright, so you know flash, like the camera flash, right?
好的，你知道闪光，就像相机闪光灯，对吧？
This big light.
这种大光。
Now flashy when you're talking about clothes or an object, it's too noticeable, right?
现在，当你谈论衣服或物品时，花哨的意思是太引人注目了，对吧？
It's too noticeable, too bright, too loud.
太引人注目、太亮、太张扬。
So for example, a black shirt is not flashy.
比如，一件黑衬衫不花哨。
But an orange shirt.
但一件橙色衬衫。
An orange shirt with buttons and bells and rhinestones, diamonds, that's flashy.
一件带纽扣、铃铛、水钻和钻石的橙色衬衫，那就花哨了。
She can also mean something that is supposed to look expensive.
她也可以指那些看起来昂贵的东西。
Okay, so that sweater was a little bit flashy according to her.
好的，所以那件毛衣在她看来有点花哨。
But also she talked about another sweater being hideous.
但她也提到了另一件毛衣很丑。
So hideous is an ugly word and it means ugly.
所以丑是一个难听的词，意思是难看。
Ugly.
难看。
Okay, so I could say this sweater is hideous.
好的，所以我可以说着件毛衣很丑。
That means it's not only ugly, it's really ugly.
那意味着它不仅难看，而且非常难看。
Okay, it's more than ugly.
好的，比难看更严重。
Alright, a hideous sweater.
好的，一件丑毛衣。
And moving on, the guy now was a little bit irritated and stressed out and he said, you
接着，那个男人有点烦躁和压力大，他说，你一直在唠叨你的新衣服。
keep yapping on about your new clothes.
新衣服。
So what is this yapping on?
那这个唠叨是什么意思？
Well, yap is a sound like yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap.
嗯，yap是一种声音，就像yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap, yap。
So yapping, to yap on about means to continue to talk and talk and talk about something.
所以唠叨，喋喋不休地谈论某事意味着继续不停地说啊说。
Because he's watching the football game on TV and she's talking and talking and talking
因为他在看电视上的足球赛，而她一直在说啊说，他很不耐烦。
and he's annoyed.
不耐烦。
So this is rude to say, stop yapping about this or stop yapping on about your game.
所以这样说很粗鲁，别唠叨这个了，或者别唠叨你的比赛了。
It's very rude.
这非常粗鲁。
It means just stop talking.
意思就是别说了。
I'm annoyed.
我很烦。
And well, then he mentioned another phrase that is pretty much the same thing, right?
然后他还提到了另一个意思差不多的短语，对吧？
Blabbering on.
喋喋不休。
To blabber, to blabber on about means to talk about something but to not really make sense.
喋喋不休，喋喋不休地谈论某事意味着谈论某事但没什么实质内容。
Okay, so it's just worthless talk.
好的，所以就是废话连篇。
So you're just talking to talk.
你只是为了说话而说话。
You're not really saying anything interesting.
你并没有说什么有趣的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
And so sometimes we make fun of people who blabber on about things because they're not
有时我们会取笑那些喋喋不休的人，因为那些事对我们不重要或者听起来很蠢。
important to us or they sound stupid.
很蠢。
All right.
好的。
Okay, so four key words there.
好的，所以这里有四个关键词。
Blabbering on, yapping on.
喋喋不休，唠叨。
Why don't we listen to them again in the dialogue?
我们不如在对话中再听一遍？
What do you think of this one?
你觉得这个怎么样？
Eh, so-so.
嗯，一般般。
And this one?
那这个呢？
Too flashy?
太花哨了？
Nah, not too flashy.
不，不算太花哨。
Oh, and this sweater from my aunt, isn't it hideous?
哦，还有我姑姑送的这件毛衣，是不是很丑？
I guess.
是吧。
Are you even listening?
你到底有没有在听？
I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
我在试着跟你说话。
And I'm trying to watch the game, but you're yapping on about your new clothes.
而我在试着看比赛，可你一直在唠叨你的新衣服。
Well, I have to decide which gifts to keep and which to exchange for better ones when
好吧，我得决定哪些礼物留着，哪些拿去换更好的，因为
I go to the Boxing Day sales this afternoon.
我今天下午要去节礼日促销。
Well, could you do me the favor of making this quick?
那你能不能行行好，快点说完？
It's the third quarter and you've been blabbering on since the first.
现在是第三节，你从第一节就开始喋喋不休了。
Oh, your precious game.
哦，你宝贵的比赛。
You watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at
你每年都看同一场比赛，每年你心爱的家乡队至少输
least three goals.
三个球。
Oh, no you didn't.
哦，你居然敢这么说。
You didn't just insult the Salisbury Seals, did you?
你刚才没侮辱索尔兹伯里海豹队吧？
Why don't you just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until the sales
你不如干脆去退掉那些蠢衣服，等促销
are over?
结束了再回来？
I might just.
我可能真会这么做。
Enjoy your stupid game.
享受你的蠢比赛吧。
And Merry Christmas.
还有圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have a couple of different phrases that we want to look at on Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看流利度构建器里的几个不同短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, so this first phrase is very closely related to the days after Christmas, especially
好的，第一个短语跟圣诞节后的日子密切相关，尤其是
here on Boxing Day.
这里的节礼日。
We've got someone who's talking about going to the stores, to the sales to exchange her
有人提到要去商店、去促销，把她的
gifts for better gifts.
礼物换成更好的。
Okay, to exchange something for something better.
好的，把某物换成更好的东西。
This is a very common construction.
这是一个很常见的结构。
It's an important phrase when talking about shopping.
在谈论购物时，这是一个重要的短语。
So when we look at this construction, you would say, to exchange this sweater for a
所以当我们看这个结构时，你会说，把这件毛衣换成
better one or for a larger one.
更好的或更大的。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can change the adjective, the word that's describing it.
所以你可以改变形容词，也就是描述它的词。
So you can say, to exchange these shoes for bigger ones.
所以你可以说，把这双鞋换成更大的。
I could also joke and I could say, I'm going to exchange my boyfriend for a better one
我也可以开玩笑说，如果我的男朋友对我粗鲁，我要把他换成更好的。
if he's being rude to me.
Okay, so to exchange something for something else.
好的，所以是把某物换成别的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And then we saw another phrase that the husband replied to when she offended him with his
然后我们看到了另一个短语，当妻子侮辱丈夫的
football team.
足球队时，他回应的那句话。
He said, oh no, you didn't.
他说，哦，不，你没说。
Didn't what?
没说什么？
I know, didn't what?
我知道，没说什么？
No, you didn't what?
不，你没说什么？
All right, so this, like you said, doesn't make sense alone, but some cultural context
好的，就像你说的，这句话单独看没意义，但一些文化背景
might help.
可能有助于理解。
In English, we often say this phrase to mean, oh no, you didn't just say that.
在英语中，我们常说这个短语来表示“哦，不，你刚才没这么说吧”。
Oh, you didn't just insult my team.
哦，你没侮辱我的队吧。
He's saying, I can't believe you just said that.
他在说，我不敢相信你刚才说了那话。
He's upset because what she said was rude or mean.
他生气是因为她说的话很粗鲁或刻薄。
Okay.
好的。
So I could say, you know, Marco, I think Ecuador sucks.
所以我可以这么说，你知道，Marco，我觉得厄瓜多尔很烂。
Oh, no, you didn't.
哦，不，你没说。
I did just say, I don't think so actually, but it's usually a response, right?
我确实说了，其实我不这么认为，但这通常是一种回应，对吧？
You have to wait until somebody maybe says something mean or something that, you know,
你得等到有人说了一些刻薄的话，或者你知道的，
really hurts her feelings or you don't agree with when you respond to this, but you're
真的伤了她的感情，或者你不同意的话，才能这样回应，但你通常
usually very, very offended, right?
非常非常生气，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
It's always a response to a comment that has made you angry or upset.
它总是对让你生气或沮丧的评论的回应。
Okay.
好的。
And then our last phrase is when they finished talking and they were fighting, she left and
然后最后一个短语是当他们说完话在吵架时，她离开并
said, I might just.
说，我可能真会。
Just what?
真会什么？
I know, just what?
我知道，真会什么？
See, again, these are common phrases, but they don't seem to make much sense alone.
你看，这些又是常见短语，但单独看似乎没什么意义。
I might just.
我可能真会。
So let's listen to, this is a response again.
所以让我们听听，这又是一个回应。
This is a response to the line before it.
这是对前面那句话的回应。
Why don't you just, just go and return all of those stupid clothes and not come back
你不如干脆去退掉所有那些蠢衣服，然后
until much later?
很晚再回来？
And she says, I might just, I might just do exactly what you just said.
她说，我可能真会，我可能真会照你说的做。
Okay.
好的。
She's threatening him.
她在威胁他。
She's saying, I might just go out and not come back for 10 hours.
她在说，我可能真会出去，十个小时不回来。
All right.
好的。
I might just do that.
我可能真会那么做。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a way to say what you said.
所以这是一种表达“照你说的做”的方式。
I might do that.
我可能会那么做。
And I'm threatening you.
而且我在威胁你。
So again, it's usually a response, right?
所以再说一次，这通常是一种回应，对吧？
Or a threat, as you said.
或者像你说的，一种威胁。
So I can say, Marco, why don't you just leave?
所以我可以这么说，Marco，你不如干脆离开？
All right.
好的。
I might just.
我可能真会。
Oh, what am I going to do in the studio alone?
哦，我一个人在录音室干什么？
All right.
好的。
So three interesting phrases there.
所以这里有三个有趣的短语。
Why don't we listen to all the words and phrases again in our dialogue one last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话中的所有单词和短语吧。
What do you think of this one?
你觉得这个怎么样？
Eh, so-so.
嗯，一般般。
And this one?
那这个呢？
Too flashy?
太花哨了？
Nah, not too flashy.
不，不太花哨。
Oh, and this sweater from my aunt, isn't it hideous?
哦，还有我阿姨送的这件毛衣，是不是很丑？
I guess.
我猜是吧。
Are you even listening?
你到底有没有在听？
I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
我在试着跟你说话。
And I'm trying to watch the game, but you're yapping on about your new clothes.
而我在试着看比赛，可你一直在唠叨你的新衣服。
Well, I have to decide which gifts to keep and which to exchange for better ones when
好吧，我得决定哪些礼物留着，哪些拿去换更好的，因为
I go to the Boxing Day sales this afternoon.
我今天下午要去节礼日促销。
Well, could you do me the favor of making this quick?
那你能不能行行好，快点说完？
It's the third quarter and you've been blabbering on since the first.
现在是第三节，你从第一节就开始喋喋不休了。
Oh, your precious game.
哦，你宝贵的比赛。
You watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at
你每年都看同一场比赛，每年你心爱的家乡队至少输
least three goals.
三个球。
Oh, no you didn't.
哦，你居然敢这么说。
You didn't just insult the Salisbury Seals, did you?
你刚才没侮辱索尔兹伯里海豹队吧？
Why don't you just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until the sales
你不如干脆去退掉所有那些蠢衣服，等促销
are over?
结束了再回来？
I might just.
我可能真会这么做。
Enjoy your stupid game.
享受你的蠢比赛吧。
And Merry Christmas.
还有圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So Boxing Day, as you said, is usually a Commonwealth thing.
所以节礼日，就像你说的，通常是英联邦国家的习俗。
In the United States, you don't really have it, right?
在美国，你们其实没有这个，对吧？
We do not.
我们没有。
My family, I don't know why, but my family sometimes celebrates that we have friends
我的家人，我不知道为什么，但我的家人有时会庆祝，我们有朋友
who come over and we have a nice Boxing Day meal.
过来，然后我们吃一顿丰盛的节礼日大餐。
But I've been told that the tradition in Commonwealth countries is to watch sporting events, local
但我听说英联邦国家的传统是观看体育赛事，当地
sporting events, and to go shopping for all these sales and bargains and exchange all
的体育赛事，然后去购物，抢购各种打折和特价商品，并交换所有
those ugly, hideous, annoying or bad gifts that you received at Christmas.
你在圣诞节收到的那些丑陋、难看、烦人或糟糕的礼物。
Right.
没错。
So it's usually like the after Christmas sales.
所以这通常就像圣诞节后的促销活动。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So if you have any special Boxing Day traditions, I'd be very curious to hear them.
所以如果你有任何特别的节礼日传统，我很想听听。
Again, not a holiday related to the sport boxing.
再次强调，这不是与拳击运动相关的节日。
It's spelled the same way and it looks the same, but they're very different.
它拼写相同，看起来也一样，但两者截然不同。
So if you have any stories or questions about the things that we talked about today, please
所以如果你有任何关于我们今天讨论内容的故事或问题，请
do let us know on our website EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there and until next time.
我们会在那里见你们，下次再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Happy Boxing.
节礼日快乐。